Guide to the Nathaniel Tarn Papers, ca. 1939-2000 M1132
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series 2. Literary Correspondence
  - Subseries M. Individual and Group Correspondence Files
    - Miscellaneous Artist Files (1970s - Present) (Box 37, Folder 5)
      Ayers, Lydia [not listed by Tarn]Hocks, Paula (Book Arts); Ignatow, Rose (Art); Jackson, Brick (Landscape Architecture, Harvard U); Klosky, Linda (Film);Kush (Film); Maher, Janet (Art); Ranney, Ed (Photography); Rossing, Ulli (Art); Stolpe, Dan (Art);Valamanesh, Hossein (Art); Vasulka, Steina (Video); Walters, Ian (Sculpture)Youngblood, Gene [not listed by Tarn]
  - Subseries N. Scholars Individual Correspondence Files
    - Arendt, Hannah (Philosophy) (Box 37, Folder 6)
      3 tls; 3 pages, 1968-70
    - Biton, Lucien (Philosophy, Buddhist Studies) [1 of 2] (Box 37, Folder 7)
      120 als, 6 handwritten postcards, 1 typed postcard; 258 pages+; French translation of NT's Berlin Festwochen paper with notes by LB. Huge bibliographical help to NT's library) 1952-+1993.
    - Biton, Lucien (Philosophy, Buddhist Studies) [2 of 2] (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - Brown, Norman, O. (Philosophy, UCSC) (Box 37, Folder 8)
      3 als, 1 handwritten postcard; 3 pages, 1983.
    - Campbell, Joseph (Mythology) (Box 37, Folder 9)
      2 als; 3 pages, 1974-5.
    - Canetti, Elias (Literature, Political Science) (Box 37, Folder 10)
      2 tls; 2 pages, 1968.
    - Scholem, Gershon (Kabbalah, U Jerusalem) (Box 37, Folder 11)
      3 als; 3 pages, 1963-70.
    - Miscellaneous Scholar Files (1960s - Present) (Box 37, Folder 12)
      Chomsky, Noam (Linguistics, MIT); Engel, W. (Psychoanalysis); Falk, Richard (Political Science, Princeton U); Gombrich, Ernst (Art History, Courtauld); Gorer, Geoffrey (Psychology, Anthropology); Gourou, Pierre (Human Geography, College de France) Hillman, James (Jungian Analysis); Leach, Bernard (Ceramics); Legman, Gershon (Folklore); Lewis, Bernard (Islam, Princeton U); Morris, Desmond (Ethology); Schachter, Zalman (Kabbalah); Sutton, G.M. (Ornithology, Oklahoma U); Yadin, Yigdael (Archaeology)
  - Subseries O. Orientalists Individual and Group Correspondence Files
    - Blacker, Carmen (Japan, Cambridge U.) (Box 37, Folder 13)
      3 als, 7 tls, 5 handwritten postcards; 13 pages, 1954-61.
    - Dumezil, Georges (Box 37, Folder 14)
      [4 als, 2 tls; not originally listed by Tarn]
    - Durt, M. (Japan, Hobogirin, Ecole Francaise d'Extreme Orient) (Box 37, Folder 15)
      7 als, 1 tls, 1 handwritten postcard; 9 pages & pages of bibliography; obituaries ofRene de Berval and Anna Seidel, 1984-92.
    - Laffont Bernard (Laos, EFEO, fellow student of NT): (Box 37, Folder 16)
      8 als, 2 tls, 1 handwritten postcard; 10 pages, 1952-
    - MacDonald, A.W. (Tibet, U Nanterre, fellow student of NT) (Box 38, Folder 1)
      13 als, 3 handwritten postcards, 1 typed postcard; 31 pages, 1951-
    - May, Jacques (Buddhism, EFEO) (Box 38, Folder 2)
      5 als, 5 tls, 1 handwritten postcard; 10 pages, 1961-64.
    - Morris, Ivan (Box 38, Folder 3)
      [5 als, 1 tls, 6 handwritten postcards, photocopied obituary from Japan House Letter, 1976; not originally listed by Tarn]
    - Stein, Rolf (Sino-Tibet, College de France) (Box 38, Folder 4)
      1 als, 1 handwritten postcard; 2 pages, 1958-61.
    - Waley, Arthur (China, Japan) (Box 38, Folder 5)
      1 handwritten postcard, 2 typed postcards, 1961-62.
    - Miscellaneous Orientalist Group Files (Mostly 1950s and 1960s) (Box 38, Folder 6)
      Bareau, Andre (Buddhism, EFEO): 1 als; 2 pages, 192.Becht, M. (S.E.Asia, U. Goettingen): 1 tls; 1 page, 1981.Boyle, J.A. (Persian, U Manchester): 2 tls; 3 pages, 1962.Coedes, Georges (S.E.Asia, EFEO, Institut de France): 1 handwritten postcard, 1960s.Cuisinier, Jeanne (S.E.Asia, Musee Guimet): 1 als, 1 handwritten postcard; 1 page, 1962.Demieville, Paul (Buddhism, College de France): 1 handwritten postcard, 1965.Daniels, Frank (Japan, SOAS): 1 als; 2 pages, 1962.De Jong, Josselyn (Buddhism, Leyden U., Canberra U.) 1 typed postcard, 1962.Dumezil, Georges (Indo-European, College de France): 1 tls, 1 page,Elisseeff, Vadime (Japan, College de France, Musee Cernuschi): 1 tls, 1 page, 1962.Gourou, Pierre: (Human Geography, College de France): 1 tls, 1 page, [missing]Leroi-Gourhan (Prehistory, Sorbonne, Director EHEE, Teacher of NT) 2 tls; 2 pages, [missing]Levy, Paul (S.E.Asia; EHE, Teacher of NT): 1 als; 2 pages, 1952.Liebenthal, Walter: (Chinese Buddhism, UC Berk.): 1 handwritten postcard, 1957.Mesman, H. R. [not originally listed by Tarn]Nakayama, Shozen (Tenri Sect): 1 tls; 1 page, 1960s (* [missing])Ogata, Shaku (Zen): 1 als; 2 pages, 1960s (* [missing]Poree-Maspero, F.: (Cambodia, Musee Guimet): 1 als; 1 page, 1967.Soymie, Michel (Japan, EFEO): 1 tls, 1 handwritten postcard; 2 pages, 1961.Tucci, Giuseppe (Buddhism, Tibet, ISMEO, U Rome): 1 tls; 1 page, 1962.Yorke, Gerald (Budhism, Publisher): 1 als, 3 tls; 4 pages, 1960.
  - Subseries P. Publishing Files: Working at Jonathan Cape, Richard Grossman, Cape, Cape Editions, and Cape Goliard Materials
    - J. Cape: mostly Old savage/young city and poetry list set up, fol 1 (Box 38, Folder 7)
      [Correspondence, mostly tls, some drafts, with Tom Maschler of Jonathan Cape, early 1960s]
    - J. Cape: NT as editor, Ø [1 of 2] (Box 38, Folder 8)
      [Correspondence, mostly tls, some drafts, photocopied newspaper articles regarding Cape publishing, mid to late 1960s]
    - J. Cape: NT as editor 1965 -1967, Ø [2 of 2] (Box 38, Folder 9)
    - J. Cape: NT as editor, 1965 -1967, I (Box 38, Folder 10)
    - J. Cape: NT as editor, 1967 -1968, II [1 of 2] (Box 38, Folder 11)
    - J. Cape: NT as editor, 1967 -1968, II [2 of 2] (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - J. Cape: NT as editor, 1967 -1968, III [1 of 2] (Box 39, Folder 2)
      [Correspondence, mostly tls, some drafts, mid to late 1960s]
    - J. Cape: NT as editor, 1967 -1968, III [2 of 2] (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - J. Cape: NT as editor, 1968 -1969, IV [1 of 2] (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - J. Cape: NT as editor, 1968 -1969, IV [2 of 2] (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - J. Cape: 1969 -1971, mainly re Neruda (Merwin, Reid, Kerrigan) (Box 39, Folder 6)
      [Correspondence, mostly tls, some drafts, regarding translations and publishing of Selected poems by Pablo Neruda; similar material regarding several of Tarn's works published by J. Cape]
    - J. Cape: 1972 -1976, mainly re Neruda (Merwin, Reid, Kerrigan) (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - J. Cape: Cape-Goliard, 1967-1969 (Box 40, Folder 1)
      [Correspondence, financial statements, meeting minutes, announcements, etc. regarding publishing activities of Tarn at Cape-Goliard]
    - J. Cape: NT blurbs, reports, etc. [1 of 2] (Box 40, Folder 2)
      [Ts and carbon of biographical notes on authors, book jacket blurbs, some correspondence and other editorial material]
    - J. Cape: NT blurbs, reports, etc. [2 of 2] (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - Cape Goliard in Santa Fe, 1971-1973 (Box 40, Folder 4)
      [Correspondence, mostly ts, regarding attempt to transfer Cape-Goliard to Santa Fe]
    - J. Cape: NT royalties [1 of 2] (Box 40, Folder 5)
      [Royalty statements, some correspondence regarding Tarn's published works through J. Cape, and others, 1960s-1970s]
    - J. Cape: NT royalties [2 of 2] (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - Berrigan, Ted: Original proofs of Sonnets. (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Blackburn, Paul: inscribed proofs of The Cities. (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Blackburn, Paul: Galley proofs of In or About the Premises (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Butor, Michel: Setting Copy of manuscript of Histoire extraordinaire (Box 41, Folder 4)
      142 page carbon typescript, corrected.
    - DeGuy, Michel: Selected poems (Box 41, Folder 5)
      Ts, some ms, with handwritten corrections.
    - Felstiner, John. Paul Celan: poet, survivor, Jew. (Box 41, Folder 6)
      [Uncorrected page proofs, bound, some handwritten notes by Tarn; not originally listed by Tarn]
    - Ginsberg, Allen: Galley proofs of T.V.Baby. (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - Hollo, Anselm: Galley Proofs of Treetop Hat. (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - Irby, Kenneth: Riding the dog (Box 41, Folder 9)
      [Photocopied ts, inscribed; not originally listed by Tarn]
    - Dakers, Charles. The winter of the world (Box 42, Folder 1)
      [Carbon copied ts; not originally listed by Tarn]
    - Eshelman, Clayton: Translation of Vallejo's Human Poems (Box 42, Folder 2)
      Original proofs [by Grove Press]
    - Fox, Robin. The violent imagination (Box 42, Folder 3)
      [Revised copy of page proof; not originally listed by Tarn]
    - Olson, Charles: First set of proofs before correction of Maximus Poems IV, V, VI (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - "X": A Quarterly Review, London (Box 42, Folder 5)
      Clippings book and proofs, plus 9 page ts program by NT to save and develop the magazine in trouble.
    - X Magazine 1962 (Box 42, Folder 6)
      [Correspondence, mostly tls, some als, regarding attempt to save magazine; ts of program regarding same,; photocopies of newspaper articles regarding magazine; not originally listed by Tarn]
    - Lowry, Malcom: Galley proofs of Selected Letters (Box 43, Folder 1)
      [Contains 6pp. photocopied ms describing Lowry's relationship with Jonathan Cape]
    - Morris, Ivan: Draft of "Kamikaze" chapter of "The nobility of failure" (Box 43, Folder 2)
      [Photocopied ts, not originally listed by Tarn]
    - Patchen, Kenneth: Selected Poems (Box 43, Folder 3)
      Setting copy, 148 page photocopy with pages of handwritten notes by NT
    - Paz, Octavio: An Introduction to Levi-Strauss (Box 43, Folder 4)
      Typed carbon with holograph notes, approx. 90 pages.
    - Ponge, Francis: Soap (Box 43, Folder 5)
      63 page carbon typescript setting copy with corrections by translator Lane Dunlop.
    - Reid, Alastair: Galley Proofs of AR's translations of Neruda. (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - Rothenberg, Diana. The mothers of the nation and other essays. (Box 43, Folder 7)
      [Proof with handwritten editing; 1 als from Pierre Joris; not originally listed by Tarn]
    - Trakl, Georg: Selected Poems. (Box 43, Folder 8)
      30 page ts plus 30 page translation by Robert Grenier of the RG, Michael Hamburger, David Luke & Christopher Middleton.
    - Weinberger, Elliot. The falls (Box 43, Folder 9)
      [Laser print copy of ts; not originally listed by Tarn]
    - Zukofsky, Louis: 55 Poems (Box 43, Folder 10)
      Galley proofs, inscribed to NT.
    - Zukofsky, Louis: All (Box 44, Folder 1)
      Galley proofs
    - Early magazine proofs, 1960s (Box 44, Folder 2)
      [Proofs of Tarn translations for Modern Poetry in Translation, The Poetry Review, and Literary Supplement 274(?)]
  - Subseries Q-1. Other Publishers' Files and Literary Materials: Correspondence
    - American Poetry Books, eventually University of New Mexico Press (Box 44, Folder 3)
      Correspondence with regard to NT's "Views from the Weaving Mountain: Selected Essays in Poetics & Anthropology," with letters from Alain Breton, Phillip Foss, Michael Heller, Michel Deguy, Julien Blaine & Edward Foster regarding the book and much reviews material, early 1990s
    - Black Sparrow Press (Box 44, Folder 4)
      51 tls, 4 cards, 50 carbons, 2 original drawings, notes, memos, etc. concerning NT's The House of Leaves.
    - Book People (Box 44, Folder 5)
      10 als; 13 pages from Bob De Lapp re various projects, 1972-75.
    - Boxkite Magazine (Box 44, Folder 6)
      [Correspondence, copies of email, publishing announcements, 1996-1998; from a more recent accession, no listing by Tarn]
    - Brillig Works Press (Box 44, Folder 7)
      File of approx. 50 pages concerning the publication of the NT - Janet Rodney work Atitlan-Alashka.
    - University of California Press (Box 44, Folder 8)
      Long, complex, eventually aborted correspondence with editor Scott Mahler re plans to publishNT's volumes in the "Autoanthropology" series, 1985-89.
    - Jonathan Cape Publishers (Box 44, Folder 9)
      13 tls, 1 telegram from Tom Maschler, mostly about possibility of Cape interest in "Scandals in the Houseof Birds," 1983-, also design materials for the Cape edition of "A Nowhere for Vallejo" (1971).
    - Chax Press (Box 44, Folder 10)
      4 tls, 2 handwritten postcards; 6 pages from Charles Alexander, regarding various projects with the Press, 1990-
    - Christopher Books Press (Box 44, Folder 11)
      Approx. 10 pages of discussion of NT's The Persephones, etc.
    - Coffee House Press [1 of 3] (Box 45, Folder 1)
      Correspondence re "Seeing America First" with design & publishing materials and correspondence mostly concerning reviews, a couple of which adverse. With reviews by Hayden Carruth, Lee Bartlett, George Myers, Jim Burns and Correspondence from Lindsay Hill; Anne Valley-Fox, Alfred Bush (Princeton U Library); Christopher Merrill; Hans Ten Berge; Peter Quartermain.
    - Coffee House Press [2 of 3] (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - Coffee House Press [3 of 3] (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - Farrar Straus Publishers (Box 45, Folder 4)
      24 letters & carbons, mostly concerning Neruda [Also contains correspondence regarding unauthorized use by Newsweek of material from Macchu Picchu]
    - Gale Publishers (Box 45, Folder 5)
      Correspondence & materials re NT's autobiography in the "Contemporary Authors" series.
    - Gale Publishers, Nathan Tarn Autobiography (Box 45, Folder 6)
      [Printouts of first, and final drafts; photocopy of page proofs; photocopy of ts with handwritten corrections; not originally listed by Tarn, found in a separate folder]
    - Grenfell Press (Box 45, Folder 7)
      2 als, 3 tls, 5 handwritten postcards, 2 typed postcards; 5 pages with Leslie Miller, possibly finest printer in US & materials on the designing and printing of Natasha Tarn's "Multitude of One," edited by NT, a very limited de luxe Letterpress edition, 1 als to Miller from Elizabeth Murray, painter, 1989-
    - Grenfell Press (Box 45, Folder 8)
      [Correspondence, copy of unsigned contract with handwritten corrections, photocopy of unsigned, blank contract form, 1991; from a more recent accession, no listing by Tarn]
    - Knopf Publishers (Box 45, Folder 9)
      Correspondence with editors Angus Cameron (See also NT at Cape Files) & Alice Quinn, mid-1970s.
    - Labrynith Press, Neruda 1984-1990 (Box 45, Folder 10)
      NT Neruda translations with illustrations by publisher Richard Bigus.
    - Marsilio Publishers, File I (Box 46, Folder 1)
      File of long correspondence with Luigi Ballerini, Eliot Weinberger, Marc Stafford etc. with much publishingmaterial, book designs, jacket designs, ms NT notes on the Marsilio crises etc, concerning the publication of NT's Scandals in the House of Birds, 1990s-.
    - Pre-Marsilio (Box 46, Folder 2)
      File re "Scandals in the House of Birds", with correspondence to & from Max Gluksman (Simon and Schuster); Andre Schiffrin & David Sternbach (Pantheon); John Glusman (Collier); Beth Haddas (UNM Press); Donald Lamm (President, Norton); Peter Turner (Shambalah); Allen Peacock (Holt); T. David Brent (U Chicago Press); Teresa May (U Texas Press); Christopher Merrill ( Gibbs Smith); Christopher Lutz (Mesoamerica); Alain Breton (Autrement/Seuil) etc.
    - Membrane Press (Box 46, Folder 3)
      1 als, 17 tls, 4 faxes; 26 pages from Karl Young, with KY poems on back of tls re NT's "The Microcosm" and later Grist website Net projects for "Alashka" and other works, 1976-
    - New Directions Publishers [1 of 2] (Box 46, Folder 4)
      Concerning NT's "Lyrics for the Bride of God" and "Alashka." 15 letters & 2 cards from James Laughlin; 23 letters & 2 cards from NT's editor; preliminary materials for Lyrics including drawings, contracts etc.; 1 als of 2 pages from Kenneth Rexroth, plus materials concerning publishing. Approx. 200 pages.
    - New Directions Publishers [2 of 2] (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - Ninja Press (Box 46, Folder 6)
      9 tls, 4 handwritten postcards from sitcom star, rafter, photographer and printer Carolee Campbell, with press materials, leading to forthcoming publication of NT's de luxe Letterpress "Architextures 1 - 7," 1993-
    - Oasis/Sherman Press (Box 46, Folder 7)
      Correspondence with Ian Robinson & Tony Frazer of the Press regarding various projects including NT's "Palenque: New & Selected Poems," 1981-
    - Oxus Press (Box 46, Folder 8)
      Correspondence with poet printer John Stathatos re NT's Letterpress edition of "Weekends in Mexico," 1981-83.
    - Perishable Press/Hamaday (Box 46, Folder 9)
      9 als from Walter Hamady, 8 proofs of collages by John Digby, carbons, notes etc. concerning theRodney-Tarn Letterpress edition of "The Forest," part of the "Alashka."
    - Permanent Press (Box 47, Folder 1)
      2 als, 7 tls, from poet editor Robert Vas Dias re Letterpress edition of Tarn-Rodney "The Ground of Our Great Admiration of Nature," part of the "Alashka," 1970-79.
    - Random House Publishers [1 of 2] (Box 47, Folder 2)
      Over 150 pages of correspondence, mostly with Nan Talese, NT's editor, press releases, carbons, jacketdesigns, blurbs etc. concerning NT's The Beautiful Contradictions; A Nowhere for Vallejo etc..
    - Random House Publishers [2 of 2] (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - Salt Works Press (Box 47, Folder 4)
      46 pages of correspondence from Marylin Kitchell re publication of works by NT and Janet Rodney & copy of publishing materials, 1983-89.
    - Sand Dollar Press (Box 47, Folder 5)
      10 als, 3 typed postcards from Jack Shoemaker with much news of R.Duncan, G.Snyder et al literary activity in the Bay Area and some Press materials, 1970-77.
    - Shambalah Publishers (Box 47, Folder 6)
      Correspondence with Peter Turner of the firm and Kent Johnson/Craig Paulenich editors re the anthology "Beneath a Single Moon: Buddhism in Contemporary American Poetry," 1990s.
    - Sun & Moon Publishers (Box 47, Folder 7)
      11 tls from poet-editor Douglas Messerli re contributions to his magazine La Bas, the S&M Gertrude Stein Awards, the Poets' Calendar, 1978-
    - Swallow Press (Box 47, Folder 8)
      [1 als, 2 tls, other material; not originally listed by Tarn]
    - Trigram Press (Box 47, Folder 9)
      1 tls, 1 handwritten postcard, mostly about NT's letterpress "October," 1969.
    - Unicorn Press (Box 47, Folder 10)
      6 ALS from Teo Savory; 3 als from Allan Brilliant, plus carbon replies, regarding NT"S translation (first in English) of Victor Segalen.
    - Correspondence with publishers & small presses [1 of 2] (Box 47, Folder 11)
      Anvil; Autrement; Backwoods Broadsides[not found]; Beacon; Book People[not found]; Burning Deck[not found]; Cadmus; Carcanet[not found]; U. Chicago; Copper Beech; Collier; Continuum; Crowell; Doghair; Doubleday; Eridanos; Farrar Straus; Firefly[not found]; Fulcrum; Gale; Gibbs Smith; Godine; Grey Fox; R. Grossman; Harcourt Brace; Howling Dog[not found]; Knopf; Labyrinth; Lapis; Logbridge Rhodes; Lorrimer; McPherson; North Point; Oleander; Overlook; Oyez; Pantheon; Penguin; Red Ozier[not found]; Shambalah[not found, listed as separate folder above?]; Station Hill[not found]; Suhrkampf/Insel; Sun & Moon[not found, listed as separate folder above?]; Talon; Tanam[not found]; Temple U; Treacle; Trout Creek; U of Warwick[not found]; Van der Marck[not found]; Villa Miseria; Viking; Wild Hawthorn[not found]; Wineberry.[Several additional publishers unlisted by Tarn are in these folders]
    - Correspondence with publishers & small presses [2 of 2] (Box 47, Folder 12)
    - NT: Misc. publishing (Box 47, Folder 13)
      [Correspondence with: Ninja Press, Heat, Quicksilver, Amazon.com, Bookworm, Shearsman, Allende, Contemoporary Authors, Routledge; and others; from a more recent accession, no listing by Tarn]
  - Subseries Q-2. Other Publishers' Files and Literary Materials: Radio Scripts
    - Celan, Paul: Word Trellis, translated by Helmut Bonheim (Box 48, Folder 1)
      38 page mimeograph.
    - Sigma Portfolio, nos. 1-10 (Box 48, Folder 2)
      Brakhage, StanCreeley, RobertLaing, R.D. McClure, MichaelTrocchi, AlexanderOthers
    - Hughes, Ted. Dogs: A radio script (Box 48, Folder 3)
      29 page mimeograph.
    - Merwin, W.S.: Poetry Reading, 9.28.1954 (Box 48, Folder 4)
      26 page mimeograph.
    - Middleton, Christopher: The Living Poets (Box 48, Folder 5)
      15 page mimograph.
    - Quasimodo, Salvatore: Poetry Reading (Box 48, Folder 6)
      9 page mimeograph.
    - Redgrove, Peter: Sermon, a Radio Script (Box 48, Folder 7)
      14 page mimeograph.
  - Subseries Q-3. Other Publishers' Files and Literary Materials: Other Scripts
    - Bartlett, Lee. Talking Poetry: Conversations in the workshop with contemporary poets (Box 48, Folder 8)
      [Photocopied proof of front material]
    - Bartlett, Lee. Conversations in the workshop with contemporary poets (Box 48, Folder 9)
      [Photocopied ts, chapters 1-7]
    - Bartlett, Lee. Conversations in the workshop with contemporary poets (Box 48, Folder 10)
      [Photocopied ts, chapters 8-end]
    - Bartlett, Lee, ed. Kenneth Rexroth and James Laughlin, selected correspondence (Box 48, Folder 11)
      [Photocopied ts, pp. 1-180]
    - Bartlett, Lee, ed. Kenneth Rexroth and James Laughlin, selected correspondence (Box 49, Folder 1)
      [Photocopied ts, pp. 181-end]
    - Bartlett, Lee. The idea of the West in the work of Thom Gunn and Nathaniel Tarn (Box 49, Folder 2)
      [Photocopied ts of essay, inscribed]
    - Bartlett, Lee. The sun is but a morning star (Box 49, Folder 3)
      [Photocopied proof, inscribed]
    - Bartlett, Lee, ed. Nathaniel Tarn, American poetry contemporary bibliography series (Box 49, Folder 4)
      [Photocopied proof, handwritten notes and corrections]
    - Preliminary bibliography, prepared for Lee Bartlett, 7/31/85 (Box 49, Folder 5)
      [Carbon copy of handwritten list]
    - Nathaniel Tarn: A bibliography (Box 49, Folder 6)
      [Dot-matrix computer printout]
    - [Bartlett, Lee. unfoldered, untitled material] (Box 49, Folder 7)
      [Photocopied articles and ts, either authored or edited by Bartlett]
    - Bartlett, Lee (Box 49, Folder 8)
      [Correspondence and photocopied ts of essays edited by Bartlett]
    - Beekman, E.M. Let it be: the ergatic mode of Netherlandic poetry and art (Box 49, Folder 9)
      [Laser print copy of ts, not originally listed by Tarn]
    - Bersenbrugge, Mei Mei: "Kindness" a play (Box 49, Folder 10)
      Acting copy of NT as actor with NT's notes, inscribed, 1992.
    - Cornelis, Jef: Tawantinsuyu, 1992-1492 (Box 49, Folder 11)
      [Laser print copy of outline for Belgian television documentary; not originally listed by Tarn]
    - Clifford, James (UCSC): On Ethnographic Authority; On Ethnographic Surrealism (Box 50, Folder 1)
      Inscribed reprints, with correspondence [Other journal articles, ts drafts and proofs]
    - Clifford, James. Other essays, book reviews, etc. (Box 50, Folder 2)
      [Photocopied ts, journal articles; not originally listed by Tarn]
    - Cornford, Adam. Decision forest, poems 1988-1995 (Box 50, Folder 3)
      [Laser printed ts, correspondence; not individually listed by Tarn]
    - Digby, John. The structure of bi-focal distance (Box 50, Folder 4)
      [2 sets of galley proofs, 1 ms; not originally listed by Tarn]
    - Friedrich, Paul (U Chicago): Linguistic Relativism & Poetic Indeterminacy (Box 50, Folder 5)
      [Photocopied] ts together with Hymes, Dell Sociolinguistics paper, 1969.
    - Heller, Michael. Some provocations concerning deep song; The true epithalamium; Poetry without credentials (Box 50, Folder 6)
      [Photocopied ts, some with handwritten corrections, some inscribed; not originally listerd by Tarn]
    - Hill, Lindsay: Socket (Box 50, Folder 7)
      Bound script together with casette andf CD recordings of long poem [unrelated correspondence; unrelated note regarding Alvarez on Sylvia Plath]